RICHARD CLOUGH - CV

0402 942 708 richardiclough@gmail.com

I'm a Digital Designer and Front End Developer from Melbourne who has worked in Advertising, On-line learning, IT, Graphic Design and print.

I'm experienced in designing/developing responsive websites and eDMs, html5, css3 and some jQuery, javascript, MySQL, SQL, php, xml, xsl and C#.

I'm also skilled in video production and Project Management. I like working on new ideas, being a part of challenging projects and bringing these projects to fruition.

ONLINE FOLIO

www.folio

<u>LinkedIn</u>

SKILLS SUMMARY

web and eDM design/development	CMS admin for WordPress, DNN and Moodle
html5, css3 and some Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, svg, php, vue.js and mySql	Git version control and Jira project management
Adobe suite, ExactTarget, Demandware Commerce Cloud, Responsys and Mailchimp	Video editing

Sizmek ad server admin

QUALIFICATIONS

Sketch, Azure

1996-1999 Advanced Diploma of Electronic Design and Interactive Media, Victoria University

COURSES

2017	General Assembly UX boot camp
2017	UX Fundamentals @ thegymnasium
2019	Introduction to React
2020	Introduction to vue.js on Pluralsight

EMPLOYMENT

Full time role at Outdoor Education Group

March - 2019 to March 2020 (currently stood down due to Covid-19)

Position

Web developer

Duties

Helping to recode and redesign internal web based staff facing portals using vue.js and php in a Semantic UI framework

Liasing with staff about requirements

Contract at Cotton On

November 2018 to December 2018 (2 months)

Front End Developer for Cotton On involved in eDM production and website updates for their <u>main</u> brands.

Contract at Priceline

March 2018 - September 2018 (6 months)

Position

eDM Developer

Duties

- Managed the implementation of a design upgrade of header and footer areas in 9 daily edms sent to over 2 million members, working out best process and liaising with external production partners throughout the upgrade process.
- Wrote ampScript to work out the dynamic reward value in an email subject line that a member needed to be able to advance to the next rewards tier.

Contracts - February 2018 to August 2015

CottonOn Front End Developer for Factorie maintaining their websites and coding new home

pages for the new <u>Australian</u> and <u>NZ</u> websites.

Che Front End Developer building eDMs for Mazda and Telstra and coded a micro-site for

Firstchoice Liquor.

Computershare Digital Designer redesigned an <u>eDM</u> for a pitch. The original is <u>here</u>.Jetstar Front End Developer coded responsive <u>eDMs</u> and sending via Sitecore.

Kathmandu Front End Developer css code for the Explore 30 Years of Adventure <u>Stackla widget</u>.

Salesforce Front End Developer coded eDMs in Exact Target for <u>Bank of Melbourne</u>.

Sending SMSs using Salesforce Exact Target for Westpac.

RACGP Front End Developer helping to finish off developing a new WordPress site.

Whybin Front End Developer coded html5 banners for Medibank.

Full time position at Apollo Media

August 2015 – December 2015 (4 months - they were a startup in the online offers industry but the position was terminated as they were running out of money).

Position

Digital Designer

Duties

Designing and building the <u>company website and designing their logo</u>. The website needed to convey the dynamic nature of the business.

Logo design which involved writing out word associations, coming up with initial sketches on paper, selecting suitable fonts, working up these concepts in Illustrator in b+w then colour. Some examples are for <u>Offers Central</u> and <u>Startup Factory</u>.

Full time position at VACC

October 2009 – June 2015 (5 years 5 months)

Position

Digital Designer

Duties

Designing and building DotNetNuke content managed websites.

Training internal staff and external clients.

Project management.

Designing and building Flash interfaces for internal clients.

Construction of html emails and xsl coding for the e-Ticket website.

Coding in html, ¡Query, JavaScript, aspx, xml and ActionScript.

Achievements

Implementing a bulk email process and building responsive eDMs.

Turning around a high volume of websites.

Part time position at Monash University, Department of Marketing, Caulfield

September 2005 - May 2009 (3 years 6 months)

Position

Project Systems and Technical Support Officer

Duties

Designing and developing course books and DVDs for distance education.

Maintenance of department websites.

Developing learning modules using WebCT Vista.

Helping staff with computer problems. Lecturing to students on website construction

Achievements

Re branding of all printed and electronic material to achieve a modern look.

Outsourced the production of materials to ensure better delivery timeframes and increased quality. Reorganizing and optimizing existing poor file structure to ensure full accessibility by other staff.

REFEREES

Felicity McIntosh Marketing Manager, Priceline, 8855 3000 Jennifer Mullins Senior Designer, Jetstar, 03 8628 3157

Tony Pool Managing Director, High Profile Events, 0418 354 180

INTERESTS

Cycling, surfing, snowboarding, swimming, bushwalking and running marathons.

Podcasts

The Web Ahead, The Big Web Show

Meet-ups

Be Responsive, The Digital Designer's Toolbox, UX Melbourne, The UX Design Group of Melbourne, UX Bookclub

Medium threads followed

Muzli (design inspiration)

Books read

<u>Design for the Real World, Gamestorming, The Inmates are Running the Asylum, The Design of Everyday Things, Design is a Job</u>

Hackathon

Evolver global sustainability jam, Melbourne November 2015

A weekend spent formulating a concept in a group of 3 other people. The final idea was called Outpost which would build sustainable working hubs, the final presentation is <u>here</u>.

Volunteering at:

<u>Robyn's Nest Animal Rescue</u> Looking after kittens and cats that were due to put down and getting them eventually adopted.

<u>Asylum Seekers Resource Centre (ASRC)</u> Assisting in food bank helping asylum seekers choose their weekly shopping.

<u>Sudanese Australian Integrated Learning (SAIL)</u> Looking after Sudanese children on Saturday mornings <u>Melbourne Open House</u> I have worked as a location volunteer.